<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="compositionLevel">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.5.1 -->
        <abbr>1.5.1</abbr>
        <gi>compositionLevel</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>None</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>An indication of whether the Object is subject to one or more processes
            of decoding or unbundling.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>A file or bitstream can be encoded with compression, encryption, etc., or
            bundled with other files or bitstreams into larger packages. Knowing the
            order in which these actions are taken is important if the original
            Object or Objects must be recovered.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>A file or bitstream can be subject to multiple encodings that must be
            decoded in reverse order (highest to lowest). For example, file A may be
            compressed to create file B, which is encrypted to create file C. To
            recreate a copy of the base file A, one would have to decrypt file C to
            create file B and then decompress file B to create file A. A
            <bold>compositionLevel</bold> of zero indicates that the object is a
            base object and not subject to further decoding, while a level of 1 or
            higher indicates that one or more decodings must be applied. Numbering
            goes lowest to highest (first encoded = 0). 0 is base object; 1-n are
            subsequent encodings. The <bold>compositionLevel</bold> should be set
            whenever possible, however it is permitted to omit (or use “unknown”) if
            it not possible to calculate this. Use 0 if there is only one
            <bold>compositionLevel</bold>. When multiple file objects are bundled
            together as filestreams within a package file object (e.g., a ZIP file),
            the individual filestream objects are not composition levels of the
            package file object. They should be considered separate objects, each
            with their own composition levels. For example, two encrypted files
            zipped together and stored in an archive as one file object would be
            described as three separate objects, each with its own associated
            metadata. The storage location of the two inner objects would point to
            the ZIP file, but the ZIP file itself would have only a single
            composition level (of zero) whose format would be “zip.” See “Object
            characteristics and composition level”.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>Non-negative integers (or “unknown”)</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Not applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item></item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item></item>
            </list>
            <list type="ordered">
                <head>Examples</head>
                <item></item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS File</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Optional</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Not repeatable</item>
            </list>
            <list type="ordered">
                <head>Examples</head>
                <item>0</item>
                <item>1</item>
                <item>2</item>
                <item>Unknown</item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Optional</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Not repeatable</item>
            </list>
            <list type="ordered">
                <head>Examples</head>
                <item>0</item>
                <item>1</item>
                <item>2</item>
                <item>Unknown</item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <table cols="4">
                <row role="label">
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell><bold>Intellectual Entity / Representation</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>File</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Bitstream</bold></cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Applicability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Not applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Repeatability</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell>Not repeatable</cell>
                    <cell>Not repeatable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Obligation</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Examples</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell><list type="ordered">
                            <item>0</item>
                            <item>1</item>
                            <item>2</item>
                            <item>Unknown</item>
                    </list></cell>
                    <cell><list type="ordered">
                            <item>0</item>
                            <item>1</item>
                            <item>2</item>
                            <item>Unknown</item>
                    </list></cell>
                </row>
            </table>
        </p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="creationmaintenance">
        <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
        <p>Composition level will generally be supplied by the repository, which
            should attempt to supply this value automatically. If the object was
            created by the repository, the creating routine knows the composition
            level and can supply this metadata. If the object is being ingested by
            the repository, repository programs will have to attempt to identify the
            composition level from the object itself or from externally supplied
            metadata.</p>
    </div>
</div>

