<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="creatingApplication">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.5.5.0 -->
        <abbr>1.5.5</abbr>
        <gi>creatingApplication</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>creatingApplicationName</p>
        <p>creatingApplicationVersion</p>
        <p>dateCreatedByApplication</p>
        <p>creatingApplicationExtension</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>Information about the application that created the object.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>Information about the creating application, including the version of the
            application and the date the file was created, can be useful for problem
            solving purposes. For example, it is not uncommon for certain versions
            of software to be known for causing conversion errors or introducing
            artifacts. It is also useful to determine whatrendering software is
            available for the digital object. For example, if you know that the
            Distiller program created the PDF file, you know it will be renderable
            with (among other programs) Adobe Reader.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>This semantic unit applies both to objects created outside of the
            repository and subsequently ingested, and to objects created by the
            repository, for example, through migration Events. The
            <bold>creatingApplication</bold> container is repeatable if more than
            one application processed the object in turn. For example, a file could
            be created by Microsoft Word and later turned into a PDF using Adobe
            Acrobat. Details of both the Word and Acrobat applications may be
            recorded. However, if both files are stored in the repository, each
            fileshould be completely described as an Object entity and linked by
            using relationship information with a <bold>relationshipType</bold>
            “derivation." The container may also be repeated to record the creating
            application before the object was ingested as well as the creating
            application used as part of the ingest process. For example, an HTML
            filewas created pre-ingest using Dreamweaver, and the Web crawler
            Heritrix then captured a snapshot of the files as part of ingest.
            <bold>creatingApplication</bold> is a frequently used semantic unit;
            however, with the introduction of more detailed environment capability,
            best practice should be to use an environment Object rather than this
            semantic unit. The use of environment Objects allows repositories to
            build complex relationships between objects and their creating or
            rendering environments. It also allows for the recording of
            relationships between environments themselves, for example, to expose
            dependencies between multiple components of complex software stacks. For
            more information on using environment Objects, see section “Special
            Topics”. However, unlike environment
            Objects, <bold>creatingApplication</bold> enables the description of
            different creating applications at different composition levels of the
            Object. It is also supported for backward compatibility. Rather than
            having each repository record this locally, it is preferable to share
            this information using environment registries.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>Container</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <table cols="4">
                <row role="label">
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell><bold>Intellectual Entity / Representation</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>File</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Bitstream</bold></cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Applicability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Not applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Repeatability</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Obligation</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                </row>
            </table>
        </p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="creationmaintenance">
        <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
        <p>If the object was created by the repository, assignment of creating
            application information should be straightforward.If the object was
            created outside the repository, it is possible this information could be
            supplied by the depositor. It might also be extracted from the file
            itself; the name of the creating application is often embedded within
            the file.</p>
    </div>
</div>

