<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="environmentDesignationExtension">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.10.5.0 -->
        <abbr>1.10.5</abbr>
        <gi>environmentDesignationExtension</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>None</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>A container for describing the designation of an environment using
            semantic units defined outside of PREMIS.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>There may be a need to supplement or replace PREMIS defined units.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>For more granularity or use of externally defined semantic units,
            extensibility is provided. Either local semantic units or metadata using
            another specified metadata scheme may be included in addition to PREMIS
            defined semantic units. When using an extension schema, a reference to
            that schema must be provided. See further guidance in “Extensibility”. If <bold>environmentDesignationExtension</bold>
            needs to be associated explicitly with any PREMIS subunit under
            environmentDesignation, the container <bold>environmentDesignation</bold> is
            repeated. Also, if extensions from different external schemas are
            needed, environmentDesignation should be repeated.
            <bold>environmentDesignationExtension</bold> is used for additional
            information about the environment designation beyond name and version in
            a structured way. This can be either additional information (such as
            release date, support dates for the software, manufacturing period for
            hardware etc.) or a finer-grained expression of version information
            (such as build number, serial number or installation guidelines). It is
            recommended to give information about the metadata used in
            <bold>environmentDesignationExtension</bold> including date the metadata
            was created, status of the metadata, internal linking IDs, type of
            metadata used and its version, message digest and message digest
            algorithm of the metadata, and type of identifier for external metadata
            links.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>None</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <table cols="5">
                <row role="label">
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell><bold>Intellectual Entity</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Representation</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>File</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Bitstream</bold></cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Applicability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Not applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Not applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Not applicable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Repeatability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Obligation</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                </row>
            </table>
        </p>
    </div>
</div>

