<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fixity">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.5.2 -->
        <abbr>1.5.2</abbr>
        <gi>fixity</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>1.5.2.1 messageDigestAlgorithm</p>
        <p>1.5.2.2 messageDigest</p>
        <p>1.5.2.3 messageDigestOriginator</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>Information used to verify whether an object has been altered in an
            undocumented or unauthorized way.</p>
    </div>
    
    <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>To perform a fixity check, a message digest calculated at some earlier
            time is compared with a message digest calculated at a later time. If
            the digests are the same, the object was not altered in the interim.
            (Note that the terms “message digest” and “checksum” are commonly used
            interchangeably. However, the term “checksum” is more correctly used for
            the product of a cyclical redundancy check (CRC), whereas the term
            “message digest” refers to the result of a cryptographic hash function,
            which is what is referred to here.)The act of performing a fixity check
            and the date it occurred would be recorded as an Event. The result of
            the check would be recorded as the <bold>eventOutcome</bold>. Therefore,
            only the <bold>messageDigestAlgorithm</bold> and <bold>messageDigest</bold> need
            to be recorded as <gi>objectCharacteristics</gi> for future comparison.
            Representation level: it could be argued that if a representation
            consists of a single file or if all the files comprised by a
            representation are combined (e.g., zipped) into a single file, then a
            fixity check could be performed on the representation. However, in both
            cases the fixity check is actually being performed on a file, which in
            this case happens to be coincidental with a representation. Bitstream
            level: message digests can be computed for bitstreams although they are
            not as common as with files. For example, the JPX format, which is a
            JPEG2000 format, supports the inclusion of MD5 or SHA-1 message digests
            in internal metadata that was calculated on any range of bytes of the
            file. For more information, see the special topic on “Fixity, integrity,
            authenticity,”.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>Container</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <table cols="4">
                <row role="label">
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell><bold>Intellectual Entity / Representation</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>File</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Bitstream</bold></cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Applicability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Not applicable (see usage note)</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable (see usage note)</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Repeatability</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Obligation</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                </row>
            </table>
        </p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="creationmaintenance">
        <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
        <p xml:lang="en">Automatically calculated and recorded by repository.</p>
    </div>
</div>

