<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="format">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.5.4 -->
        <abbr>1.5.4</abbr>
        <gi>format</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>formatDesignation</p>
        <p>formatRegistry</p>
        <p>formatNote</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>Identification of the format of a file or bitstream where format is
            defined as the organization of digital information according to preset
            specifications.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>Many preservation activities depend on detailed knowledge about the
            format of the digital object. An accurate identification of format is
            essential. The identification provided, whether by name or pointer to a
            format registry, should be sufficient to associate the object with more
            detailed format information.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>A bitstream embedded within a file may have different characteristics
            from the larger file. For example, a bitstream in LaTeX format could be
            embedded within an SGML file, or multiple images using different
            colorspaces could be embedded within a TIFF file. <bold>format</bold> must
            be recorded for every object. When the bitstream format can be
            recognized by the repository and the repository might want to treat the
            bitstream differently from the embedding file for preservation purposes,
            <bold>format</bold> can be recorded for embedded bitstreams. At least
            one subunit (i.e. either <bold>formatDesignation</bold> or
            <bold>formatRegistry</bold>) must be present if this container is
            included, or both may be used. If the subunit
            (<bold>formatDesignation</bold> or <bold>formatRegistry</bold>) needs to be
            repeated, the entire format container is repeated. This allows for
            association of format designation with a particular set of format
            registry information. For example, if the precise format cannot be
            determined and two <bold>format</bold> designations are recorded, each is
            given within a separate <bold>format</bold> container. In such cases the
            <bold>formatNote</bold> element can be used to distinguish between the
            cases where either (i) it is known that the file complies with multiple
            format definitions or (ii) it is known that the file complies with one
            of these formats but there is insufficient knowledge to distinguish
            between them. The <bold>format</bold> container may also be repeated for
            multiple format registry entries. If a file or bitstream is in an
            unknown format then a <bold>formatDesignation</bold> element should be added
            with formatName set to unknown. See “Format information”.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>Container</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Not applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item></item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item></item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS File</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Mandatory</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Repeatable</item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Mandatory</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Repeatable</item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="creationmaintenance">
        <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
        <p>The format of a file or bitstream should be ascertained by the repository
            on ingest. Even if this information is provided by the submitter,
            directly in metadata or indirectly via the filename extension,
            recommended practice is to identify the format independently by parsing
            the file when possible. If the format cannot be identified at the time
            of ingest, it is valid to record that it is unknown, but the repository
            should subsequently make an effort to identify the format, even if
            manual intervention is required.</p>
    </div>
</div>

