<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="inhibitors">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.5.6.0 -->
        <abbr>1.5.6</abbr>
        <gi>inhibitors</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>inhibitorType</p>
        <p>inhibitorTarget</p>
        <p>inhibitorKey</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>Features of the object that inhibit access, use, or migration.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>Format information may indicate whether a file is encrypted, but the
            nature of the encryption also must be recorded, as well as the access
            key.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>Some file formats allow encryption for embedded bitstreams. Some file
            formats such as PDF use passwords to control access to content or
            specific functions. Although this is actually implemented at the
            bitstream level, for preservation purposes it is effectively managed at
            the file level; that is, passwords would not be recorded for
            individually addressable bitstreams. For certain types of inhibitor
            keys, more granularity may be requiredin local applications. If the
            inhibitor key information is identical to key information in digital
            signatures, use those semantic units.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>Container</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Not applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item></item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item></item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS File</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Optional</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Repeatable</item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Optional</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Repeatable</item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="creationmaintenance">
        <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
        <p>Inhibitors are more likely to be present on an object ingested by the
            repository than applied by the repository itself. It is hard to detect
            during ingest if a file is encrypted, but this may be known from the
            context in which it is ingested. Therefore, information about inhibitors
            should be supplied as metadata with submitted objects when possible.</p>
    </div>
</div>

