<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="originalName">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.6.0 -->
        <abbr>1.6</abbr>
        <gi>originalName</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>None</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>The name of the object as submitted to or harvested by the repository,
            before any renaming by the repository.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>This unit allows preservation system to rename files (for internal
            management and storage purposes) but still retain the name of the object
            that was submitted. The name used within the preservation repository may
            not be known outside of the repository. A depositor might need to
            request a file by its original name. Also, the repository may need to
            reconstruct internal links for dissemination.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>This is designed to be used to hold the name supplied by the immediate
            source before ingest by the repository. This may or may not be the
            initial name that the object had (e.g., the source could have renamed a
            file when it ingested it from a previous source and not retained its
            initial name). In addition it may or may not be the name that the object
            was called in the immediate source before the repository (e.g., the
            source system might hold it with one name but rename it upon export to,
            say, its truly original name). The original name of the object must be
            designated in the Submission Information Package (SIP) (since the
            repository cannot in general work it out by other means) although it may
            or may not be the primary identifier of the object in the SIP. The
            object may have other names in different contexts. When two repositories
            are exchanging content, it would be important for the receiving
            repository to know and record the name of the Intellectual Entity or
            Representation at the originating repository. In the case of IEs or
            representations, this may be a directory name.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>None</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <table cols="4">
                <row role="label">
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell><bold>Intellectual Entity / Representation</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>File</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Bitstream</bold></cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Applicability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Not applicable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Repeatability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Not repeatable</cell>
                    <cell>Not repeatable</cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Obligation</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Examples</bold></cell>
                    <cell><list type="ordered">
                            <item>"Animal Antics"</item>
                    </list></cell>
                    <cell><list type="ordered">
                            <item>N419.pdf</item>
                    </list></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                </row>
            </table>
        </p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="creationmaintenance">
        <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
        <p>This value would always be supplied to the repository by the submitter or
            harvesting application. How much of the file path to preserve would be
            up to the repository.</p>
    </div>
</div>

