<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="relationship">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.13.0 -->
        <abbr>1.13</abbr>
        <gi>relationship</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>relationshipType</p>
        <p>relationshipSubType</p>
        <p>relatedObjectIdentifier</p>
        <p>relatedEventIdentifier</p>
        <p>relatedEnvironmentPurpose</p>
        <p>relatedEnvironmentCharacteristic</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>Information about a relationship between this Object and one or more
            other Objects.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>A preservation repository must know how to assemble complex objects from
            component parts (structural relationships), rigorously track digital
            provenance (derivation relationships) and document the links between
            parts of a rendering stack in a Representation Information Network
            (dependency and documentation links). Documentation about relationships
            between different objects is crucial to these purposes.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>Most preservation repositories will want to record all relevant
            relationships.In complex scenarios, PREMIS might not be able to express
            rich enough structural relationships to be the only source of structural
            metadata. Many formats for representing structural information may be
            used instead of the semantic units specified here. This information must
            be recorded, and some implementations may record it by using other
            structures (e.g. METS). Structural relationships between the fileand
            representation level are necessary to reconstruct a representation in
            order to ascertain that the representation is renderable. A record of
            structural relationships at the representation level may be necessary to
            render the representation. Structural relationships at the bitstream
            level can relate bitstreams within a file. Structural relationships
            between Intellectual Entities may be used to record logical containment,
            such as between an article and an issue, or physical containment, such
            as between a page and a book. Derivative relationships at the file,
            representation and Intellectual Entity level are important for
            documenting digital provenance.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>Container</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS Intellectual Entity</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Optional</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Repeatable</item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS Representation</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Not applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Optional</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Repeatable</item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS File</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Not applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Optional</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Repeatable</item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="simple">
                <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                <label>Applicability</label>
                <item>Not applicable</item>
                <label>Obligation</label>
                <item>Optional</item>
                <label>Repeatability</label>
                <item>Repeatable</item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </div>
</div>

