<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="significantProperties">
    
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.4.0 -->
        <abbr>1.4</abbr>
        <gi>significantProperties</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>1.4.1 significantPropertiesType</p>
        <p>1.4.2 significantPropertiesValue</p>
        <p>1.4.3 significantPropertiesExtension</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>Characteristics of a particular object subjectively determined to be
            important to maintain through preservation actions.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>Objects that have the same technical properties may still differ as to
            the properties that should be preserved for future presentation or
            use.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>At least one of the <gi>significantPropertiesValue</gi> and
            <bold>significantPropertiesExtension</bold> subunits must be present if
            this container is included, or both may be used.</p>
        <p>The choice of whether a property is significant is subjective. Some of
            these properties can be directly measured while others can only be
            determined subjectively. </p>
        <p>For example, a PDF may contain links that are not considered important
            and JavaScript that is considered important. Or future migrations of a
            TIFF image may require optimization for line clarity or for color; the
            option chosen would depend upon a curatorial judgment of the significant
            properties of the image.</p>
        <p> Listing significant properties implies that the repository plans to
            preserve these properties across time and requires them to survive
            preservation action acceptably; for example, to be maintained during
            emulation orafter format migration. It also implies that the repository
            would note when preservation action results in modification of
            significant properties.</p>
        <p>In practice, significant properties might be used as measures of DATA
            DICTIONARY preservation success, as part of quality checking the results
            of a preservation action or evaluating the efficacy of a preservation
            method. For example, if the listed significant properties are not
            maintained after application of a particular preservation method, it may
            indicate a failure of the process or that the method is not well suited
            to the type of material.</p>
        <p>More experience with digital preservation is needed to determine the best
            ways of representing significant properties in general, and of
            representing modification of significant properties.</p>
        <p>The semantic units included in the <bold>significantProperties</bold>
            container aim to provide a flexible structure for describing significant
            properties, allowing general types of aspects, facets or attributes of
            an object to be declared and to be paired with specific significant
            details about the object pertaining to that aspect, facet or
            attribute.</p>
        <p>For example, some repositories may define significant properties for
            objects related to facets of content, appearance, structure, behavior,
            and context. Examples of facet:detail pairs in this case are as follows
            (note that each facet:detail pair should be contained in a separate,
            repeated <bold>significantPropertiescontainer</bold>):
            <bold>significantPropertiesType</bold>= “content”</p>
        <p><bold>significantPropertiesValue</bold>= “all textual content and images”</p>
        <p><bold>significantPropertiesType</bold>= “behavior” significantPropertiesValue
            = “editable”</p>
        <p>Other repositories may choose to describe significant properties at a
            more granular attribute level; for example:</p>
        <p><bold>significantPropertiesType</bold>= “page count”</p>
        <p><bold>significantPropertiesValue</bold>= “7”</p>
        <p><bold>significantPropertiesType</bold>= “page width”</p>
        <p><bold>significantPropertiesValue</bold>= “210 mm”</p>
        <p>Further work on determining and describing significant properties may
            yield more detailed schemes to facilitate general description.</p>
        <p>Representing modification of significant properties as a result of
            preservation action also requires further work. One possible way
            involves the use of Object and Event information: Object A has the
            significant properties volume and timing, which are recorded as
            <bold>significantProperties</bold> of A. In migrated version B, the
            timing is modified, which is noted in the <bold>eventOutcome</bold> of the
            migration Event. Only volume is listed as a significant property of
            B.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>Container</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <table cols="4">
                <row role="label">
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell><bold>Intellectual Entity / Representation</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>File</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Bitstream</bold></cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Applicability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Repeatability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Obligation</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                </row>
            </table>
        </p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="creationmaintenance">
        <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
        <p xml:lang="en">Significant properties may pertain to all objects of a
            certain class; for example, the repository can decide that for all PDF
            files, only the content need be preserved. In other cases for example,
            for media art, the significant properties may be unique to each
            individual object. Where values are unique, they must be supplied by the
            submitter or provided by the curatorial staff of the repsoitory.</p>
        
    </div>
</div>

