<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="storage">
    <head>
        
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.7.0 -->
        <abbr>1.7</abbr>
        <gi>storage</gi>
        
    </head>
    
    <div type="semanticcomponents">
        <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
        <p>contentLocation</p>
        <p>storageMedium</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="definition">
        <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
        <p>Information about how and where an entity can be found. For bitstreams
            this means the location within a file. For files this means the physical
            location in one or more storage systems. Starting with PREMIS version
            3.0, <bold>storage</bold> is applicable to representations. For physical
            representations such as system disks or printed versions of digital
            files, this means the location of the physical object, such as a shelf
            location. For digital representations this means the location of the
            digital object in a storage system, if all files in the representation
            can be found in this same location. </p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="rationale">
        <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
        <p>It is necessary for a repository to know where to locate objects and to
            associate the <bold>contentLocation</bold> of digital objects with the
            <bold>storageMedium</bold>.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="usagenotes">
        <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
        <p>For digital representations and files, the <bold>storage</bold> container
            should be repeated if there are two or more copies that are identical
            bit-wise and managed as a unit, except for the medium on which they are
            stored. To use this repetition, the copies must have a single
            <bold>objectIdentifier</bold> and be managed as a single object by the
            repository. Note that many storage systems (e.g., hierarchical storage
            management systems, cloud storage providers etc.) will provide only a
            single reference to an object even though it may store multiple copies.
            For bitstreams, the <bold>storage</bold> container could be repeated if
            there is more than one way of getting to the start of the bitstream
            within a file (e.g., byte offset from start or byte offset from end).
            For representations of physical Objects, the storage for both physical
            copies of content (for example, a paper copy of a digital object) and
            for physical environment instances (for example, a custom computer chip)
            can be specified. See the “Environment” section in “Special Topics” for more information on physical Environments.</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="datatype">
        <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
        <p>Container</p>
    </div>
    
    <div type="entity">
        <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
        <p>
            <table cols="5">
                <row role="label">
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell><bold>Intellectual Entity</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Representation</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>File</bold></cell>
                    <cell><bold>Bitstream</bold></cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Applicability</bold></cell>
                    <cell>Not applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                    <cell>Applicable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Repeatability</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                    <cell>Repeatable</cell>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <cell><bold>Obligation</bold></cell>
                    <cell> </cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                    <cell>Optional</cell>
                </row>
            </table>
        </p>
    </div>
</div>

